- [Instructor] Okay, so we're going to do a few fixes
in the application just
to make sure everything works properly.
As a developer, it's important to understand
or see that you're not alone when you're doing typos,
you're doing little mistakes here and there,
and it happens to me too.
So I want to go through the exercise
of figuring those things out together.
So right now, let's go back to here.
Let's reload this.
And there's a few things that we can see that are wrong.
So this is the string ref.
You can read on it here and make the changes.
It's not a big issue, but if you want to fix it,
you can fix that one.
The first thing that I need
to fix here is the unique key prop for PlayerList.
So let's go in PlayerList and take a look at what that is.
Let's go here and go in PlayerList.
And here, what I'm doing is .id, but it's _id.
That's what I get back from the actual database.
So that would fix the first thing that we have.
Now when we update the player right now,
something's not working here.
So when we click on the application,
if you go here and I close this.
And I try to load my players here as the current player.
It's not working, so something's off.
So I'm going to go into the App.jsx,
where we have that particular element that's happening here.
So here, I am basically passing the function,
but it's not updating.
So let's go here and see why.
So I have my function here,
everything's set properly,
setState, currentPlayer, blah, blah, blah.
But as I scroll up,
what I realize is that I didn't declare
that particular function that I'm passing in my constructor.
So I need to do this now.
So I'm going
to do this.updateCurrentPlayer = this.updateCurrentPlayer
and then bind this.
So basically, what I've done here is I've declared it
in my constructor.
So when you're using basically the state
and passing down functions into your components
like we're doing here, then using them as a prop,
you need to declare it in your class component here
in your constructor.
Very important to do this.
Okay, now there is one other thing
that I want to fix here in my app.
Here is the menu.
I don't like the style for this one.
So what I'm going to do is basically redo
that particular line here,
and I'm going to do a div
of className='nav-wrapper
blue darken-1'.
And I'm going to make an a tag with the href
of forward slash with a className of brand-logo.
Again, I'm leveraging the Materialize styles here
and I'm going to call the title Soccer Management.
There you go, and I've fixed this here too.
All right, so now what we need to do is go inside
of our PlayerForm 'cause clearly,
we have an issue with our PlayerForm as well
'cause when we try to submit a new player,
it's not working.
So at first, I was like, "No, there's nothing wrong here.
So I'm doing the submit properly,
the function is done properly here."
And everything else is good up until I got to this,
and it took me in between videos a bit
to figure out my typo here.
And if you read the error when you submit,
it literally tags this
to the actual localhost port 5173,
which is the React application.
So at first I was like, "Okay, this is weird."
And then I went back here and I said,
"Oh wait, I forgot to do my forward slashes here."
So it wasn't an official URL that Axios could take,
and then send the submit form.
And that was the error, then that was why it was working.
So if we save that, everything is good.
I'm going to refresh just out of my good nature,
and I'm seeing a little problem here with the menu.
Let's go back to our menu.
This is a minor thing that we can fix.
I'm in the app, yes, okay.
The problem is I didn't do this with a nav wrapper,
so I need to change this very quickly.
So I'm going to do that right now, ,
and then close that out here,
and then that should fix it.
There you go. Okay, so I have my title, I have my players.
If I select my player, now they're going to show here.
So we're all good, and now I need to add a new player.
So I'm going to just test it with Manuello Henrietto.
Phone, 444555123,
there you go, me6@me6.com
ADD PLAYER, Refresh.
We have the new player here. We're all good to go.
Okay, so now you have an application
that can add new players and see a list of our players.
But what about deleting
or updating the current list of players?
We won't cover these elements in this course,
but you could easily use the same methods we've covered
for adding new contacts or listing now
that you have a base code
with Axios making the request to the APIs.
Simply add a button in the players single,
following the button syntax from Materialize.
And then in the same component,
add a call to Axios to delete the current player.
You could also leverage a form we created,
and pull the values into the field
to update a particular player within Axios PUT to the API.
A lot of code needs to do these transaction could be written
by you and I challenge you to keep going on your own.
Also, there are a few additional values we've defined to add
to the application, such as the player is a coach,
strength value, et cetera.
We minimize the typing of all these different values
on the front end as they were repetitive.
But this would be a good exercise for you
to test your knowledge and practice.
So this completes this application,
and feel free to challenge yourself and keep going with it.